<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Khoi Can Dev</title>
    <link href="https://khoican.dev/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://khoican.dev" />
    <updated>2020-02-23T23:53:47+07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Khoi Can Dev</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://khoican.dev</id>

    <entry>
        <title>The Last Lecture - Randy Pausch</title>
        <author>
            <name>Khoi Can Dev</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://khoican.dev/takeaways-the-last-lecture-randy-pausch.html"/>
        <id>https://khoican.dev/takeaways-the-last-lecture-randy-pausch.html</id>
            <category term="Book"/>

        <updated>2019-11-20T22:40:51+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Short stories of a professor that has an incurable cancer. The book, which you can call a complete transcript of his presentation, cover many moments that affect his life in&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p id="mcetoc_1d92nooau1">Short stories of a professor that has an incurable cancer. The book, which you can call a complete transcript of his presentation, cover many moments that affect his life in his childhood, university student, work life and relationship. He set his dreams when he was a child, and commit to them since then. A great inspiration for someone who works with computer like me.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1d92nom7u0">Quotes</h2>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1d92npdml2">Relationship</h3>
<ol>
<li>Don't finish someone's sentences. And talking louder or faster doesn't make your idea any better.</li>
<li>If you wait long enough, people will surprise and impress you.</li>
<li>Watch What They Do, <em>Not What They Say</em></li>
<li>A Bad Apology Is Worse Than No Apology.</li>
<li>Proper apologies have three parts:
<ol>
<li>What I did was wrong</li>
<li>I feel badly that I hurt you</li>
<li>How do I make this better?</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1d92nplf93">How To Live</h3>
<ol>
<li>The brick walls are there for a reason. They're not there to keep us out. The brink walls are there to give us a chance to how how badly we want something.</li>
<li>Experience is what you get when you didn't get what you wanted.</li>
<li>Time is all you have. And you may find one day that you have less than you think.</li>
<li>Luck is indeed where preparation meets opportunity.</li>
<li><span id="reviewTextContainer470406484" class="readable"><span id="freeText17831765479674834442">Even if in a position of strength, whether at work or in relationships, you have to play fair. Just because you're in a driver's seat, doesn't mean you have to run people over.</span></span></li>
<li>If your car has a dent, you don't have to have it removed. It could be a statement of who you are. Not everything needs to be fixed.</li>
<li>Whether you think you can or can't, you're right.</li>
<li>If I could give three words of advice, they would be "tell the truth." If I got three more words, I'd add: "All the time."</li>
<li>We cannot change the cards we are dealt, just how we play the hand.</li>
<li>I mean, I don’t know how <i xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">not</i> to have fun. I’m dying and I’m having fun. And I’m going to keep having fun every day I have left. Because there’s no other way to play it.</li>
<li>Am I a fun-loving Tigger or am I a sad-sack Eeyore? Pick a camp. I think it’s clear where I stand on the great Tigger/Eeyore debate.</li>
<li>Sometimes, all you have to do is ask.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1d92o29vk4">Work</h3>
<ol>
<li><span id="reviewTextContainer19929770" class="readable"><span id="freeText14759365834385401636">A lot of people want a shortcut. I find the best shortcut is the long way, which is basically two words: work hard.</span></span></li>
<li>Time must be explicitly managed, like money.</li>
<li>Ask yourself: Are you spending your time on the right things?</li>
<li>Complaining does not work as a strategy. We all have finite time and energy. Any time we spend whining is unlikely to help us achieve our goals. And it won’t make us happier.</li>
<li>It’s not how hard you hit. It’s how hard you get hit ...and keep moving forward.</li>
<li>Adding manpower to a late software project makes it later. (This is now known as “Brooks Law.”)</li>
</ol>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
